Hi  我是Glenn  来自Android Audio团队
Hi, I'm Glenn, from Android Audio.
我喜欢集成事物  特别是音乐和软件
I like putting stuff together, especially music and software.
今天我想分享一些我一直在学的
Today, I want to share some cool tricks
音频格式中的一些很酷的技巧
I've been learning about audio formats.
在我们的职业生涯中  我们一直被
For most of our careers, we've been
告知要用整型或者是定点运算来处理音频
told to use integer, or fixed point arithmetic for audio.
我们都用整型是因为它有一些好处
There's some good reasons why we all use integers.
他们很棒
They're great.
定点运算也一样
Fixed point, too.
从数模转换器
From digital to analog converters,
到CD  到USB音频  整型和定点运算到处都是
to CDs to USB audio, integers and fixed point are everywhere.
我们都知道的是  黑客躲避浮点型就像我们用basic//todo
As we all know, hackers avoid Floats as much as we do basic.
让我们来看看我们为什么不用浮点型
So let's review the reasons why we don't use floating point.
首先  这里没有浮点型
First of all, it's not there.
没有支持浮点型的单元
No affordable floating point unit.
这是我的首个FPU
This was my first FPU.
每秒5000次浮点运算  非常昂贵
5,000 flops, and so expensive, we only
我们只在绝对要用的时候用到它
used it when we absolutely had to.
浮点型很大
Floats are very big.
每个要4字节
Four bytes each.
好吧  这个好恶心
OK, this is just gross.
但是你懂的
But you get the idea.
浮点型很大
Floats are huge.
这个是我喜欢的
This one is my favorite.
罗马的衰落  我的意思是浮点型
The decadence of Rome, I mean Floats.
如果你有浮点型的CPU和内存
Even if you have the CPU and memory for floating point,
这种奢侈地浪费资源的行为简直是在犯罪
it's just sinful to waste resources so extravagantly,
或是在浪费很奢侈的东西
on something that's clearly a luxury.
这就像在用32位的  嗯
It's kind of like using a 32-bit, um--
我是说用64位的Ant来显示一个布尔值
I mean 64-bit ant to represent a Boolean.
你现在知道发生什么了吧
You do realize this is what actually happens now?
显然  浮点型已经过时了
So, Floats are clearly out.
或者是我们认为的
Or so we think.
现在  我们想要从音频的数字中获得什么
Now, what do we really want from our numbers in audio?
宽动态范围的软编码和声音  一致的//todo
Wide dynamic range for soft and loud, consistent accuracy
精度范围  大量的空间
across that range, and lots of headroom.
没有裁剪
No clipping.
让我们考验一下我们的朋友
So let's examine our friends.
整型和定点运算
Integer and fixed point.
首先  整型
First, integer.
这很简单
This is simple.
相邻的值不同
Adjacent values differ by one.
用二进制补码表示二进制
Integers are represented in two's complement binary.
定点运算也一样  与一个隐式的二进制点
Fixed point is the same, with an implied binary point.
对于音频来说  这个隐式的二进制点
For audio, the implied binary point
几乎总是在左边最重要的bit上
is almost always at the left of the most significant bit.
并且常量的两个相邻值不同
And adjacent values differ by a constant power of two.
它仍然是二进制补码的二进制
It's still two's complement binary.
早些时候  我们认为浮点型可以解决
Now earlier, we thought Floats work out.
但是真的吗
But are they really?
不管怎样我们先来看看  不用担心
Let's look at them anyway-- don't worry,
这只是为了让这些更有趣
it's just to make fun of them.
或者并不是
Or maybe not?
浮点型以定点尾数开始
Floating point starts with a fixed point mantissa.
尾数的比特数代表总体的精确值
The number of bits in the mantissa determines the overall accuracy.
然后我们加上一个整型的指数
Then, we add an integer exponent.
这增加了范围
This increases the range.
指数越大  范围越大
The wider the exponent, the more range.
这里有一个标记位  但是我们现在先忽略它
There's a signed bit too, but we'll ignore that for now.
现在  记住我们在音频中想要的东西
Now, remember what we all want in audio.
宽动态范围的软编码和声音  一致的//todo
Wide dynamic range for soft and loud, consistent accuracy
精度范围和大量的空间来防止音频丢失
across that range, and lots of headroom to prevent clipping.
让我们来看看浮点型在这三点中表现如何
Let's see how well Float does on all three.
我们从动态范围开始
We'll start with dynamic range.
这里有浮点型的一个公式  结合正弦  尾数
Here's the formula for a Float, combining sine, mantissa
和指数
and exponent.
戏剧性的结果是指数提升了动态范围
Turns out the exponent increases the dynamic range dramatically,
和整型或定点运算相比
compared to integer, or fixed point.
你需要交付多少db或bit给内容是有争议的
How many db or bits you need for content delivery is controversial.
我不谈论这个
I'm not going there.
能确定的是  在内部  宽动态范围是有用的
What is certain, is that a wide dynamic range is useful internally.
浮点型提供了
And Float provides that.
现在  我们来看一下准确性
Now, let's look at accuracy.
记住  相邻的整型值不相同
Remember, adjacent integer values differ by one,
相邻的常量的两个定点值不相同//todo
and adjacent fixed point values by a constant power of two.
听起来很好
Sounds good at first.
在定点值中  虽然差异是常数//todo
Within some fixed point, though the differences are constant,
但是相邻整型值之间的比率值
the ratios between adjacent values
不是常数  整数  或定点值
are not constant, for either integer, or fixed point.
哇喔
Whoah!
怎样做才能保持一致的准确性
What's that going to do to consistent accuracy?
我们在最需要精确度的地方失去它
We lose accuracy, where we need it most.
安静的信号
Quiet signals.
在这个图表中  比率接近2
In this graph, the ratios approach two
且变得平稳  而不是1
as we get quieter, instead of one.
这是浮点型的比率图表
And here's our ratio chart for Float.
相邻值之间的比率
The ratios between adjacent values
基本上是不变的  而且接近1
are now approximately constant, and approach one.
距离则是对数
The distances are logarithmic.
注意这些密集的点接近于0
Notice the tighter packing near zero.
这意味着整个完整的动态范围一致的准确性
This means consistent accuracy across the full dynamic range.
所以  软编码和声音听起来都很不错
So, soft and loud both sound great.
最后  让我们来看看空间
Finally, let's look at Headroom.
空间是安全区域  在名义上的最高级别之上
Headroom is a safety zone, above your nominal maximum level,
在中间运算中防止丢失数据
to help prevent clipping during intermediate calculations,
和卡顿
and transience.
这是浮点型的闪光点
This is where floating point really shines.
在中间运算中几乎不可能
It's almost impossible to clip samples
出现样本丢失
during intermediate calculations,
因为浮点值的范围很大
because the range to afloat is astronomical.
使空间最大化
Maximize your headroom.
所以  是时候换角度思考了
So, it's time to think differently.
这里有一些引人注目的原因
Those were some compelling reasons
让你考虑使用浮点型在你的下一个音频APP中
to consider floating point, in your next audio app.
使用浮点型不要求你是一个
You don't need to be an expert in numerical analysis
数值分析方面的专家
to use floating point.
浮点值并不是灵丹妙药
But floating point is not a panacea.
你扔需要知道一些其他的  这里就有一些
You do need to know the gotchas, and there are a few.
请查看视频最后的参考资料
Check out the references at the end,
提示和技巧将会帮你
with some tips and tricks that will
避免一些最常见的问题
help you avoid the most common problems.
所以  我建议你在你的下一个APP中使用浮点型
So, I ask you to consider floating point in your next audio app.
难道这些理由不足以让你使用它吗
And what about all those reasons not to use floating point?
现在  你可能在期望我
Now, you're probably expecting me
说一些不好的理由
to say those reasons aren't valid anymore.
嗯嗯
Uh uh.
这些理由还是有正确的地方的
Some of them are still true.
特别是第一点
Especially the moral depravity one.
但是好处就意味着  是时候捏住鼻子
But the benefits mean it's time to hold our noses,
然后考虑浮点型
and consider floating point anyway.
做个预先警告
Be forewarned.
如果你使用浮点型  别人
If you use floating point, others
就会在你做代码回顾的时候羞辱你
will try to shame you during code reviews.
所以  做好迎接光荣的准备吧
So, be prepared for glory.
自豪吧
Be proud.
穿着大红的F  你会做得更好
Wear the scarlet F, you'll do fine.
浏览此链接以获取更多信息
Make sure to check out this link for more information.
我是Glenn Kasten
I'm Glenn Kasten.
感谢观看
Thank you for watching.